In eight more hours, we will witness
the grand reunification ceremony
of Hong Kong and China.
This is a moment we have
been waiting for 155 years.
WELCOME BACK, HONG KONG
The midnight of July 1st, 1997
is approaching steadily.
YUANLONGLI INTERNATIONAL GARDEN
What was it again? Good
afternoon, Sir.
YUANLONGLI INTERNATIONAL GARDEN
No parking here.
No parking here. Go.
Hey!
Where did she go?
A relative of someone here?
Look. That guy.
NEW YORK BLOCK
Why is he in black?
They didn't even pick up the kid
after they bumped into him.
Qiang.
Eighteenth floor?
I thought no one lived there anymore.
Qiang.
Do you see what's on her back…
-What are you staring at?
-Oh my!
Nothing.
I have a meeting at the provincial office.
Keep your eyes open.
Make sure nothing happens.
Okay.
The janitor said she went
to the 18th floor.
18th floor? It's already haunted
before they raided
the prostitution rings here.
Eighteenth floor?
Wasn't the underground club raided?
Where did they go?
It's you, Ma Qiang?
Weird. Both fire exits are locked.
Where could those two have gone?
Don't touch anything.
Go downstairs to find them.
What's the matter, Wang?
Wang Wuluan. What are you doing?
Why is there a pair of footprints here?
There's no one in there.
Call 110!
Puking before you go to work.
This must be your first day, rookie.
I'm getting motion sickness.
You drove too fast.
Liu. After you're done puking,
come here. I want to talk to you.
Come here. I want to talk to you.
Listen.
We've been asked
to team up at the last minute.
Even though it's quite ad hoc,
rules must be established.
I know. Captain Feng said
you came to assist
and would go back after a week.
-They asked me to…
-They asked you
not to give me any trouble. Right?
They asked me to guide you
through our work.
Who's guiding whom now? You're a rookie.
Do you know how many years
I've been doing this?
But you've been working
in a police station.
I studied for six years to become
a criminal police officer.
You only know the theories.
Enough chatting.
The old guide the young.
That's the rule in the squad.
Captain Feng only told me
to partner up with you.
Even in a partnership,
there's a pecking order.
I'm the mentor. You're my apprentice.
When we work, you listen to me.
So, how do you want to proceed today?
That's the right attitude.
Listen. I was in charge of Yuanlongli
when I was working in the police station.
Back then, the workers dug out a cenotaph.
After that, the residents
became paranoid and superstitious.
They keep calling the police for nothing.
-So?
-So, we stay put.
We let them cool their heads.
I disagree.
If paranoia isn't solved in time,
it might evolve into a collective risk.
Did I just establish
the pecking order for nothing?
I'm your mentor. You're my apprentice.
-If I tell you to do this…
-Mr. He.
Can we work now?
Mr… Mr. He? You think I'm a mechanic?
More like someone who fixes gas lights.
What gas lights?
Gaslighting. Gaslight.
Did you just tell me to bugger off?
So rude.
Something bad happened
in Yuanlongli just now.
Do you want to know?
A woman was carrying a man on her back
up to the 18th floor.
How creepy!
A man and a woman.
Both covered in black.
Gone.
Not even bones left.
I saw with my own eyes.
You saw with your own eyes.
Meng. Come here.
Not even bones left. I see.
Officer He. That's my cloak.
Didn't you say it killed two people?
It's now evidence.
I have to keep it to examine it.
Who else witnessed it?
YUANLONGLI INTERNATIONAL GARDEN
POLICE
Calling the police
for the slightest inconvenience.
How many times has it been?
You two.
One is from the residents committee.
One is from the security team.
Instead of dispelling
the superstition, you fanned it.
Making a fake police call is a crime.
Do you understand?
Yes.
There's no victim and no culprit.
Their relatives
also didn't call the police.
There's nothing to file a case here.
Besides, the police already came here.
Come. Sign it.
One more week,
and I'll go back to my previous post.
Do you get what I mean?
It's the last sprint.
Don't go to the criminal department
and bother me for something trivial.
If I get a case,
I won't be able to go back.
-Just sign it.
-I… Where do I sign it?
This young man is…
Oh, he's Liu. My apprentice.
He just graduated.
It's his first day at work.
He's new here.
Do look after him, will you?
Hello. I'm Ran. R-A-N.
Also, I'm not his…
WITNESS' STATEMENT
Hi. Are you Li Tieling?
So the woman and the old man
disappeared when you turned around.
Yes. The woman was wearing a white dress
and blue leather heels.
She vanished just like that.
-Do you want to know how they vanished?
-Yes.
Re-enact what you did
when you chased the rickshaws away.
Then turn around and look at me.
Okay. No parking here. Go. Go.
Are you insane?
Then I…
He's gone. He's gone.
I'm here.
You assumed they would cross
the main road to enter the gate.
But they stuck to the wall,
just outside your line of vision.
This is called a psychological blind spot.
Watch me do it again.
You explained the trick.
Why bother doing it again?
It's called re-enactment.
According to the Western
investigation procedures,
you must imagine that you're the culprit
and re-enact what they did.
Enact what?
Re… enact?
From this place to that block,
taking the main road is the shorter route.
Why did they take a detour then?
Come with me.
Where are we going?
Case closed.
They didn't ask for criminal police.
Captain Feng got a call and asked us
to assess the situation personally.
We didn't even enter the premises.
Isn't that too irresponsible?
Irresponsible?
Making a fake police call
is irresponsible.
It's a waste of police resources too.
Sir, we over-reacted here. Please go back.
I'll just talk to Officer Qu.
Wait. Officer Qu?
Which one? Qu Dahai?
Yes. I called 110, and Officer Qu came.
He's inside the building?
I'll go and take a look.
YUANLONGLI INTERNATIONAL GARDEN
That woman carried the old man
and stood still here.
She even took off her heels.
What else did she do?
She did this.
I can fix it.
I'll pick it up.
So clumsy. Hurry up.
Officer Qu. Careful. The footprints.
What are you doing?
PATTIA CLUB
He Yuanhang. What brings you here?
Han. Shouhu.
What are you doing here? Go back.
Did I say you could go back?
Continue.
Your footsteps are making a mess.
Are you examining
or contaminating the crime scene?
Who says I'm examining the scene?
I'm looking for the culprit. Continue!
Touch anything if you dare.
Excuse me. You're blocking the evidence.
See? The criminal police are working.
Now work!
You little…
I like him. What's his name?
Ran Fangxu. My apprentice.
Top scorer from People's Public Security
University of China, PPSUC.
PPSUC?
Your apprentice?
Why would I have
brought him here with me, otherwise?
Jealous?
Want to join the criminal department?
I can talk to Captain Feng for you.
You can have him.
Sounds good?
This wooden plank is so annoying.
Well, it's all thanks to your mentor.
He did this when he raided
the prostitution ring.
That's right.
Let me borrow this.
He is not my mentor.
You liar.
-Ma Qiang.
-Yes.
-Open the door.
-Okay.
Forgive me. I conducted an experiment.
What are you doing?
Seriously? It's called enaction. Right?
Re-enactment.
There's a nail on the door frame.
The dust by the door frame is gone.
I suppose someone
hung the black cloak here.
The height of it is enough
to cover an adult
when someone opens the door.
A prank then?
But there's one unanswered question.
The footprints disappear here.
They didn't go back the way they came.
Qu Dahai and his men stepped
all over the place.
How can we trace footprints now?
Dust can be thick.
New and old footprints have gaps.
You're so thorough, Fangxu.
You left no stone unturned.
Unlike someone I know
who has peanuts for a brain.
All empty inside.
You have peanuts for a brain.
Move.
How can you be a criminal police
with such a bad core strength?
Size 37 feet.
Carrying an old man
all the way from outside.
She must be a strong woman.
These must be the basics
you learned in PPSUC.
They don't teach you common sense.
You little…
What did you see?
Four cigarette butts.
Judging from their looks,
they were used less than two hours ago.
Judging from the charred ends,
the smoker was anxious.
Some of them were thrown away
after a few puffs were taken.
Do you recognize the brand?
How much does it cost?
A packet of Yuxi cigarettes.
Mainly for bosses.
Twenty yuan for one packet.
Are you sure there were
no footprints in the room?
I guess so.
We came looking for the culprit.
Of course, we walked around.
Then don't walk that much.
BEIJING TRAVEL
Officer He. Officer Qu.
Calm down. Tell me clearly.
Okay. I checked all the rooms.
There's no one.
I also checked the security cameras.
No one took the elevator.
Two adults couldn't possibly
vanish just like that.
They must be somewhere.
Both sides of the staircase
are locked from the outside too.
Where else could they go?
It looks like a locked room.
Three paths.
The staircase is locked.
The elevator has security cameras.
Exactly. It's weird.
That's why I called Captain Feng.
I think you should file a case.
File what case? What case?
Let me explain everything to you.
The door is locked from the outside.
You can't open it.
See? They left like this.
This door isn't locked.
File a case?
This is just a prank. Okay?
Officer He. This isn't right.
The staircase. The window.
And the padlock. The padlock!
What? Isn't it…
-Surround them from both sides!
-On it!
Stay right there!
Wait for me.
Sorry, I'm in a hurry.
Take the next one. Sorry.
Stealing a lock before the police.
How dare you!
Stop right there.
Stop right there. Stop right there.
What are you doing?
He Yuanhang!
I caught him. He Yuanhang! Help me!
Why are you yelling?
Stop yelling.
You took the elevator,
but you're still slow!
He has already run away!
Be careful.
NEW YORK BLOCK
Officer He!
Officer He. Officer He.
There are bad guys in the block.
They scared my son.
Were you running around
the staircase just now?
Why did you go to the 18th floor?
He saw everything.
He even bumped into them.
Tell me.
Why did you lock us in the staircase?
I was scared you'd come after me.
Hey there. It's okay.
You saw the two missing persons, right?
I saw their hands.
It's not human hands. They have claws.
Claws?
Is that coming from your exaggeration?
See? I told you so.
They bumped into him,
and they didn't even pick him up.
They bumped into him how many times?
Just once.
And he got bruises everywhere?
It's as if he has been run over.
-Little one, your bruises are…
-I fell when he chased after me.
Officer He. Listen.
We put the padlock
when we were checking the place.
I don't care who put it there.
I just want to know if it was locked.
No, it wasn't.
It wasn't locked?
That means those two people
could leave through that door.
I guess so.
You examined the place for hours,
and you couldn't figure out
one simple staircase.
Qu. Given your lack of competence,
how am I supposed
to put in a few good words for you?
Say no more.
Don't just stand there.
This is just a prank.
Go back and pack up. Case closed!
I already told you so.
The reunification of Hong Kong
is more interesting.
Officer He. We need to file a case.
Then explain. Why?
Ma Qiang said there were
no footprints in the western corridor.
They also said the cloak
took two people away.
They make things up all the time.
How can I believe them?
Be patient. Let me finish.
Just tell me what you want to do.
I just want to get to the bottom
of this case.
Listen carefully.
One, this isn't even a case.
Two, if you want to investigate,
find another partner. Don't…
Don't bother you as you're about
to go back to being the deputy director.
I get it.
I knew you were that kind of person
from the start.
Just gaslighting people.
Did you scold me just now?
YUANLONGLI INTERNATIONAL GARDEN
WEIYANG PUBLIC SECURITY BUREAU
NANSHAN BRANCH
This one is…
Kid.
Did you see Ran?
Lan? Who?
R-A-N.
You must be new here.
-I…
-He Yuanhang. Stop yelling.
Can't you see we're working here?
I'm looking for Ran.
Something happened in Yuanlongli again?
Go back to your work.
Don't pester me.
Ran Fangxu is slacking
in the archive room.
Do talk to him.
He could've answered my call.
I called him for five minutes.
All of them are so lazy.
He is Mr. He.
Old Geezer. Why are you here again?
Don't call me old geezer.
Where is Ran?
Why do you need him?
It's none of your business. Where is he?
You eat to sleep, sleep to eat.
Where's your spirit?
Everyone gets bored
when they work here every day.
Why don't you ask them
to put me on patrol duty?
Ran Fangxu!
MEN'S TOILETS
UNDER MAINTENANCE
Ran Fangxu!
Just because you're standing
on the toilet bowl
doesn't mean I won't know you're here.
Come out. Open the door.
Sir. I have diarrhea.
I'm vomiting and pooping.
I can't go anywhere.
Are you an ostrich
that poops while standing?
Come out now.
I'll count to three.
Count to 300, and I still won't come out.
Just you wait.
-One.
-Sir.
-Two.
-What are you doing?
-Sir?
-Three!
Hey!
Sir,
I just finished this lesson plan.
Oh, you and your useless theories again.
I have a case that concerns my reputation.
You have a reputation?
I'll tell you on the way.
Sir, I have work to do.
Bah! This is what you call work?
Some people love to be on patrol duty.
Some people just want to stay
in the archive room.
I can't catch a break at all.
What are you implying?
Mister,
can you drive slower?
Slower?
Back then, on our first gig together,
I drove slightly faster
and you got your panties in a twist.
I… I have motion sickness.
Besides, it wasn't like you drove fast
to investigate the case.
Nonsense!
Don't make it sound
like I'm irresponsible.
When we first worked together,
you didn't even bother memorizing
my surname.
I…
All right. This is it.
I'm not driving over there.
That place brings bad luck.
Pay up.
Okay.
Let's go.
You didn't tell me
we'd come to Yuanlongli.
Come on. If I told you,
you wouldn't want to come with me.
Come down now.
I'm just here on a business trip.
I'll be back after a week.
You're going back to Beijing after a week?
Did you bring me with you
for another case?
His name is Han Zi'ang.
He went missing less than 48 hours ago.
They haven't filed the case yet.
I've talked to the parents,
and I think there's more
than meets the eye.
I agreed to help them.
After all these years, I've become
quite good at finding missing persons.
They call me human radar.
If there's more to the case
than meets the eye,
then hand the case over to the police.
As I said, they haven't
filed the case yet.
I'm just a kind citizen who wants
to locate the missing child.
Since we're here already,
just help me out.
-My reputation is at stake here.
-Sir, I'm a teacher now.
And you're retired.
We can't investigate cases anymore.
Let's just leave.
Don't give me excuses.
Eighteen years ago,
I too was eager to leave after a week.
But a jerk came to me
and said I was irresponsible.
Sorry, sir.
Back then, it was my fault.
It's not your fault.
It's not anyone's fault.
If I must put the blame on something,
it's on the fact that you didn't build
a good relationship with me.
I didn't build
a good relationship with you?
-I kept addressing you as my mentor then.
-Nonsense!
Stop wasting my time. Get out of the car.
Slow down. Slow down.
You keep saying that you don't
want to come to Yuanlongli.
But once you're in here,
you walk briskly like an eager visitor.
That's because
you were gaslighting me again.
I see you're not on social media.
It's not called gaslighting anymore.
It's called brainwashing. Come.
Let's take a break.
Don't. We can't stay here for long.
This building is haunted.
Once in a while, it'll kill someone.
Two policemen died here.
Died here?
One of them was in charge of this place.
-What's his name again?
-He something.
When they found him, his body was impaled
by a spear on this wall.
It was horrifying.
Quickly now.
You two look horrifying.
Mister. We weren't even talking about you.
Why are you yelling at me?
-Sir.
-Don't hold me back.
Tell me. How was I impaled on this wall?
Oh my…
Sir, Yuanlongli houses
a superstitious community.
You know that already.
Why pick a bone with them?
If I don't scold them now,
the next one they curse will be you.
You're dead.
You can't step on the 18th floor.
Yuanlongli
-Eighteenth floor, 18 pillars
-Eighteenth floor…
Eighteenth floor with 18 pillars
Eighteen pillars
With 18 men to carry them…
They are still singing the nursery rhyme?
If you hadn't insisted
on investigating the truth,
this so-called haunted building
would've taken more lives.
Eighteenth floor with 18 pillars
Eighteen bodies, 18 heads
He Yuanhang.
You owe me a meal.
For what?
WEIYANG CULTURAL CENTER
Aren't you investigating a case?
I jumped the queue for you
and got the report ready.
Six more days till I return
to the police station.
What case is this?
Come on. They sent
the evidence for analysis.
Two sets of fingerprints.
Four cigarette butts.
One cloak. And one security footage.
It's all under your name.
I…
It was all good.
Except Mr. He Yuanhang
and I don't get along well.
Can you get me another partner?
Changing your partner on your first day?
What did He Yuanhang do?
I don't think he has…
Captain Feng. I'm here
to find my apprentice.
Let me reiterate.
I am not your apprentice.
Young and petty.
It's just a term. No need to overreact.
I'm not being petty.
I'm being responsible here.
Captain Feng. See this?
Our temperaments don't match.
Our personalities are different.
We argue often,
and that'll affect our work efficiency.
Since I'm going back
to the police station,
why don't you give him another partner?
I'll hand over whatever I'm doing to him.
I see you two are putting
on an act in front of me.
Just be frank. What help
do you need from me?
Captain Feng.
This is not an act.
-I mean it. I want to break…
-Break up!
-Captain Feng.
-I am.
Captain Feng. The embarrassing case
from Yuanlongli.
The residents have come forward.
What now?
He Yuanhang. Mind your words.
Maybe officers like you
think it's nothing.
But the residents are getting manic.
They are saying the two missing persons
are the Black and White Guards.
And the building is their hunting ground.
And they are singing this.
Yuanlongli
Eighteenth floor
Eighteen bodies, 18 heads
Nonsense.
Someone among them
is trying to spread a rumor.
Captain Feng.
When they were building Yuanlongli,
they found a tomb.
It was a cenotaph
from the Three Kingdoms period.
There were no human remains inside.
The Residents Committee
just has to clarify the rumors.
Why mobilize the criminal police?
The problem is that Yuanlongli
is a complex neighborhood.
You see all sorts of people there.
Someone went missing yesterday.
Then today, a nursery song
like that appeared.
Everyone is scared.
-Please help us find the truth.
-He Yuanhang.
What was yesterday's case about?
Qu Dahai had already determined
that it was just a prank.
-But I…
-It wasn't a prank at all.
Captain Feng.
I interviewed the witnesses last night.
I can confirm three things.
One. There are no footprints
deeper into the corridor.
Two. The security guards
put the padlock there.
Three. Mr. Liang broke the glass
of the door leading to the staircase.
Therefore, the exit path
Officer He described yesterday
could never have existed.
The disappearance of those two persons
is still an enigma.
Well said! I agree with Fangxu.
I also agree with him.
Trivial problems, when neglected,
will fester into major problems.
Rumors can be destructive.
Some say that He Yuanhang
only got into the criminal department
because of his connections.
Take a seat.
But in fact, I chose him
from among many candidates.
Captain Feng.
Even though he never receives
proper training,
the place he's in charge of consistently
has the highest clearance rate.
What does this mean?
It means he has something
neither of us has.
In certain areas,
he will be quite helpful.
But of course, you can also
help him with your expertise.
Do you get what I mean now?
Captain Feng,
about the case in Yuanlongli…
Both of you will follow up with the case.
Officer He. Don't let me keep you.
I have to go now.
POLICE BY THE PEOPLE
FOR THE PEOPLE
MISSING DOG
Stop.
Rewind a bit.
Here.
It looks like a cigarette.
Can you tell which brand it is?
No. No way.
No way.
It looks like
marks left by a medical paste.
What are you doing?
Did I sign this before you gave it
to the Forensic Department?
Is the Forensic Department
strapped for cash lately?
He Yuanhang! We're not done studying it.
What does studying it serve?
Hey!
MISSING PERSONS
FEMALE: AROUND 20-25 YEARS OLD
MALE: AROUND 55-60 YEARS OLD
This is your number?
Yes. Should I use yours?
I don't have a pager.
Why do you not want to stay
in the criminal department?
You're too naive.
Officer He.
I believe we should first figure out
the motive behind their disappearance.
Isn't it clear enough? It's a prank.
Then tell me.
Why did the woman take off her heels
when she entered the elevator?
And why did she hold the heels
with her teeth?
Why did the old man press all the buttons
in the elevator before he left?
Because it's a prank. Understood?
Then why did they disappear
in that locked space?
-Why, why, why.
-Why did they…
Do you only know how to repeat why?
Our priority should be to find out
how they disappear in Yuanlongli.
That's redundant.
Find them, and you'll know
how they disappear.
Listen to me.
Find them, and they
will give you the answer.
Why should I listen to you?
Fine.
NANSHAN TYPEWRITING
Wait.
You see those rickshaw riders?
Should we have a wager?
Go to them.
If you can get their names,
I'll take orders from you.
If you fail to do that,
you take orders from me.
What do you say?
No, thanks.
Didn't you want to find out how they left?
I remember the missing persons
came on a rickshaw.
Mister, where do you want to go?
-Mister, where do you want to go?
Hello, everyone.
I am from the criminal department
of Nanshan police station.
I'd like to know…
Hey!
Hey…
Mister!
Do you understand why I didn't leave
the police station's number?
You look like an imperial envoy
who visits a village.
Wearing a pair of slacks
won't make it easier to catch a criminal.
You look posh.
You speak like an officer,
and you couldn't even get the names
of those rickshaw riders.
You're telling me you want
to investigate the case?
Officer He, when I was studying,
I looked into renowned cases of missing
persons, both local and international.
Specifically, their psychology
and behavior.
My judgment tells me that
the Yuanlongli case isn't just a prank.
Have you looked into the missing person
case in Weinan Street, Weiyang City?
No.
Do you know why?
After I was assigned
to Weiyang, for 22 years,
whenever someone or even a pet
in my district went missing,
I could find them with my eyes closed.
I didn't need to study
renowned missing person cases.
But hanging up posters
and waiting for calls is too passive.
And your initiatives
bring trouble to others.
To whom?
When you sent the evidence
to the Forensic Department,
why did you leave my name?
I only came here yesterday.
They won't acknowledge my signature.
Get out of the car.
Get yourself back to the station
and withdraw all analysis requests
under my name.
Take me to Yuanlongli.
I'll examine the scene again.
Did I owe you a favor? Get out of the car.
It's an official vehicle.
Why should I leave?
Official vehicle?
This is my personal car.
I paid for the petrol from my own pocket.
And I printed these things
with my own money.
You think you're the only one
with integrity? I have it too.
Get out of the car.
Officer He.
Based on my deduction,
the unusual behavior
from those two missing persons
seems to be motivated
by some external coercion.
Many homicides also started
as a missing person case.
What homicide?
There has never been a murder on my turf.
You came, and there's a murder
all of a sudden.
Murphy's law. Whatever you don't
want to happen will happen.
I don’t care about your law.
I don’t care about your homicide.
You lost the bet just now.
So you take orders from me.
I now order you to return to the station
and withdraw the analysis requests
under my name.
He Yuanhang!
You do not have what it takes
to be a criminal police officer.
PATTIA CLUB, THAI MASSAGE